Finding aid for the Barbara Aziz broadcasts collection
Bentley Historical Library
- Radio Tahrir and related material, 1989-2014
  - November 24, 2009, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:57); (Aziz speaks with Zuheir Jennan on new private universites in Syria, part 1 of Phil Kai with hiphop UK-based Palestinian artist Shadia Mansour on her work and the Palestinian struggle, Dawn Elder and Dr. Mohanad Hamami on the LA Arab charity music concert. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Syrian educator Zuheir Jennan, vocalist Shadia Mansour, LA-based world music promoter Dawn Elder and Dr M. Hamami. Topics: Syria, Arab world education, Palestine, HipHop, world music.)
  - December 1, 2009, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:16); (Author Marston discusses her children\'s book, "Christmas in Baghdad", Dr Nassar talks about PTSD experience by war care givers with open phones. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: author Elsa Marston, psychologist Dr. Paul Nassar. Topics: literature, disorders from war and conflict.)
  - December 8, 2009, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:47); (Nasr interviews children's author Dennis about writing and publishing about Native Americans, review with directors whose work is showing at Africa Diaspora Film festival. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: author Yvonne Dennis, South Sudan activist Nesrin Allamine, filmmakers Asha Shaaban and Khalid Al-Haggar. Topics: children's literature, Sudan, Egyptian film.)
  - December 22, 2009, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:50); (Iranian American Amir Parsa talks about writing and his recent book, Nasr interviews US Muslim women about veil rules. Hosts/Producer: Sarah Malaika, Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: Iranian author Amir Parsa, NJ Muslims. Topics: Iran, literature, Egypt, women.)
  - December 29, 2009, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:22); (We replay a presentation by Walid Khalidi at the UN conf on Palestine, Sally Sharif interviews sister Ronda about basketball, book reviews. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: Palestinian historian Walid Khalidi, Sally Sharif, Ronda Sherif. Topics: Palestine, ME history, Muslim Americans, sports.)
  - 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:08:23); (Tamara Issak interviews members of the rap group Native Deen in CA. Hosts/Producer: Tamara Issak. Interviewees/Guests: HipHop music group Native Deen. Topics: HipHop, Islam, Native Deen.)
  - 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:39); (Over-voice by readers, in English and Arabic, recording from testimonials in Lebanon regarding prisoners. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Lebanese voices from Lebanon Radio. Topics: Palestine, resistance to occupation.)
  - 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:04); (Poetry recitation, interviews, music, commentary on Palestinian leadership and on-the-ground realties, sufi music and word composition. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Poet Mohja Kahf, musician Ibrahim Gonzalez. Topics: Palestine; Israeli's confiscations and home demolitions, Arab American poetry, introduction to detained Palestinian leader Abu Marzouk.)
  - January 5, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:32); (BN Aziz interviews Egyptian director Khaled Al-Haggar on his films and Egypt\'s film industry, "Questioning the Veil" author Marnia Lazreg refutes arguments re head covering in Islam, Muslim Hiphop artist Kamal Imani, listeners. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Egyptian film director Al-Haggar; NYC professor of sociology Marnia Lazreg; NJ based musician Kamal Imani. Topics: Egypt, film, gender and Islam, women, world music.)
  - January 12, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:51:31); (Poem by Kamal Imani, Hassen Abdellah reviews US government policy re bomb threats from article by Joe Quinn on www.SOT.net, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: announcements by Aziz, comment by Abdellah. Topics: Islam HipHop, announcements, US policy and threats.)
  - January 19, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:41); (BN Aziz interviews Bin Wahab\'s observations visiting Palestine West Bank and Israeli lobby and Black American governments representatives, Sherif reviews book "Sugar Comes from Arabic", Inter-city Muslim Action Network on NYC arts event. Hosts/Producer: Sarah Malaika, Sally Sharif. Interviewees/Guests: US activist Doruba Bin Wahab; Inner-City Muslim Action Network (IMAN) members Ibrahim Abdul Matin, Raul Miller, Sumaiya Ahmed. Topics: Palestine, book review, announcements, world music.)
  - February 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:59); (Sudanese musicians and singers in studio play selections, commentary by musicians, impresario Dawn Elder and Dr. Mutawakil Muhammed. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Dawn Elder with Sudanese musicians and vocalists, Sudanese historian Dr Mutawakil Mohammed. Topics: Sudan, musical history.)
  - February 23, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:11:00); (Featuring audio CD of speeches by Malcolm X Malik Shabazz with fundraising. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz and team. Interviewees/Guests: fundraiser. Topics: Malcolm X special.)
  - March 2, 2010
    - Part 1 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:36); (Anderson discusses plans for Malcolm X Museum and educational programs on Malcolm X, Ahdami (part 1 of 3) discusses art and music in Islamic ideas and history. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Sam Anderson of Malik Al-Shabbaz (Malcolm X) NY Museum, Islamic scholar Abdellah Adhami. Topics: Malcolm X, Muslim Americans, Islamic ideas and history, world music.)
    - Part 2 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:29:03); (Aziz critically reviews film "What Muslim Think" with clips. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: clips from film "What Muslims Think" (Part 2 of March 2 program). Topics: Islam, Muslim Americans, Muslim views, world music, film review.)
  - March 9, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:10); (Attorney Khalidi reports on campaign and petitions to save Jerusalem Arab cemetery\'s destruction by Israelis, Syrian student\'s radio production "A Damascus street", scholar Adhami on Arab Islamic semantics (part 2 of 3). Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Sally Sharif. Interviewees/Guests: Chicago attorney Deema Khalidi, Sheik Abdellah Adhami, Syrian student Baraa Kadra. Topics: Palestine, cultural destruction, Islamic ideas and history, announcements.)
  - March 16, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:04); (Obituary of Iraqi painter Laila Attar (archive), documentary "Iraq: How Can I Forget", Tamara Issak reviews Circassian history and culture, Aziz commentary on Israeli policy against Palestinians with house and land demolitions. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Iraqi testimonies from 1991, Tamara Issak. Topics: Iraq, art, children, sanctions, Circassian, announcements, civil rights, Palestine, Israeli expansionist policy, world music.)
  - March 23, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:27); (Poem by Mohja Kahf, Laila Khali reviews campaign in support of Gaza Palestinians, US scholar Ginan Rauf reviews Arab writing by American Arabs and its value to heritage and history. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Sally Sharif. Interviewees/Guests: Arab scholar Ginan Rauf, Palestinian activist Laila Khalil. Topics: Arab literature, Arab Americans, announcements, word music, Iraq.)
  - March 30, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:40); (Abdellah and guest review US news coverage of US-based Christian terror. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: NJ attorney Mohammed Bashir. Topics: Muslim Americans, what is a terror threat.)
  - April 6, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:54); (NY Census reps talk about Arab American population, author Salaita talks about the poverty of liberal thought, subject of his new book, Sherif interviews American Muslims for Palestine rep on Gaza conditions campaign. Hosts/Producer: Sarah Malaika, Sally Sharif. Interviewees/Guests: NYC census-takers Ayman Ghali and Ahmed Shedeed, Virginia Tech U. professor and author Steven Salaita, Palestinian activist Laila Khalil. Topics: Muslim Americans, US census, literature and cultural bias, Palestine, world music.)
  - April 13, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:31); (Malaika interviews jazz fusion musician Al-Saffar head of "Saffafir", producer Tamara Issak interviews Kader Nathow on Circassian history. Hosts/Producer: Sarah Malaika, Sally Sharif. Interviewees/Guests: Amir Al-Saffar jazz musician, US-Circassian historian Kather Nathow. Topics: music, Circassian history.)
  - April 20, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:46); (Aziz interviews Islamic scholar Abdellah Adhami (part 3 in a series), Aziz with Iranian director Bahman Ghobadi about his films, including latest "Persian Cats," Nisreen Alamine reviews Sudan and preparations for elections. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Sheik Abdella Adhami in Damascus commentary, Bahman Ghobahi Iranian filmmaker, Nisreen Alamine Sudanese activist. Topics: poetry, Islamic ideas, Syria, Iran, film, Sudan elections.)
  - April 27, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:27); (US poets HipHop artist Adhami speaks with Tamara Issak, poems from our archive by Lisa Mohammed, Kazim Ali, Mohja Kahf, report on Newburgh case by attorney Susan Adley. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Sally Sharif. Interviewees/Guests: poets Ghath Adhami, Kazim Ali, Lisa Mohammed, Mohja Kahf, Shadia Mansour, attorney Susan Adley. Topics: civil rights, poetry, Muslim and Arab spoken voice artists, world music, announcements.)
  - May 4, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:20); (Syrian activist historian Nadia Khost reviews attempts to protect and restore old houses in Damascus city (Arabic and English), Kamal Imani, NJ based poet and lyricist, talks about origin and aims of his work. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Syrian urban historian Nadia Khost, NJ rap artist Kamal Imani. Topics: Syria, Arab history, Muslim American hiphop, world music.)
  - May 11, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:34); (Bashir and Abdellah discuss US Justice's approach to US terror threats, callins. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: NJ attorney Mohammed Bashir. Topics: US justice, terror threats, callins.)
  - June 22, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:19); (Poem and interview with Kazim Ali, Aziz interviews Syrian radio host Nidaa (Arabic and English) regarding her work in Syrian media, world music, Women in Islam announcement of Betty Shabbaz awards in NYC. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: poet Kazim Ali, Syrian broadcaster Nidaa Hussein, Women in Islam Sarah and Farhana. Topics: Arab American poetry, Syria, Arab media, Muslim Americans, women.)
  - June 29, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:47); (Palestinian Poet Abu Arab (in Arabic); Tamara Issak interviews poets at RAWI conference in Ann Arbor: Halaby, Hazo, Nye, world music, Hassen Abdellah on "material support" and ramifications of US anti-terror laws. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: poets Palestinian Abu Arab, Arab American poets. Topics: civil rights, poetry, Anti-terror laws, civil rights.)
  - July 6, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:17); (Mohja Kahf poem "Move Over", Reem Nasr reports on NYC Muslims campaigning for recognition of Muslim holidays, Sundus Mahmoud interviews professor and author of "Popular Proverbs", Aziz updates of civil rights case on attorney Lynne Stewart, Aziz reviews Azzawi\'s new data on Iraq\'s humanitarian conditions. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Reem Nasr, Sundus Mahmoud. Interviewees/Guests: South Carolina professor Nasr Isleem. Topics: Muslim Americans, school holidays, Arabic language,world music, civil rights.)
  - July 10, 2010, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:41); (Aziz reviews 1990-2003 Iraq sanctions history with Tahrir archival documents, Ros Pourzal reviews conditions inside Iran and comments on sanctions. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Iranian American commentator Ros Pourzal. Topics: sanctions, Iran, Iraq.)
  - March 1, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:06); (Middle East political news report, Malaika interviews Moh Keita of CPJ reports on global media and censorship in East African countries, Tamara Issak comments on emerging Arabic revolution music, Remi Kanazi discusses his work and aims, and recites from new poetry collection "Poetic Injustice". Hosts/Producer: Sarah Malaika, Tamara Issak. Interviewees/Guests: Mohammed Keita of Committee to Protect Journalists (CPJ) Palestinian US poet Remi Kanazi. Topics: Middle East news report, world music, journalism, global media, East Africa and North Africa, Palestine protest poetry, world music.)
  - March 15, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:56); (UN diplomats and US Pakistanis report on flood conditions in Pakistan and community activists speak about relief efforts, "Through Latino Eyes" panel of NYU young Muslim women testimony on converting to Islam and living a Muslim life produced by Reem Nasr. Hosts/Producer: Saadia Aslam. Interviewees/Guests: UN Pakistan diplomats, NYU Muslim Women. Topics: Pakistan flood relief, Muslim Americans, religious conversion, world music.)
  - March 22, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:48:29); (Brief Middle East news report, Seattle-based prof and analyst Dr Karem Donna comments on Congressman Peter King\'s congress hearings and "The New McCarthyism"; SF-based author and theater artist Ms. Nilufar Talesbi talks about Iran inspired theater, writing and music. Hosts/Producer: Sara Malaika, Saadia Aslam. Interviewees/Guests: Seattle based professor and analyst Dr Karem Donna; writer/theater Nilufar Talesbi author of "Fire Angels". Topics: Muslim Americans, civil rights, Iran, music, anti-Muslim policies, world music.)
  - March 29, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:14); (Nasr speaks with nutritionist and dietitian Sarah Amer about health in Islam, Zeiba Ikbal and (web dating founder Half-Our-Deen) Ali Artikani address standard marriage practices and today\'s young Muslim needs and new dating sites. Hosts/Producer: Reem Nasr, Tamara Issak. Interviewees/Guests: nutritionist Sarah Amer, guests writer Zeiba Ikbal and (web founder) Ali Artikani talk and "Salam Hearts"\' Kamal Sharawi discuss Muslim marriage services and dating. Topics: Muslim Americans, marriage, nutritionist, ME news summary, world music, listener calls.)
  - April 5, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:20); (NJ activists announce Juan Cole's event in NJ and current peace actions, UCLA Law professor; Aslo Bhali comments on UN resolutions and war developments in Libya. Hosts/Producer: Sarah Malaika, Saadia Aslam. Interviewees/Guests: NJ Peace Action representative M Hoffman. Topics: ME news, civil rights, local peace actions, world music.)
  - April 12, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:50:48); (Tamara Issak speaks to Yemini journalist Nadia Safaf on women in journalism and Yemen politics and society, G. Khamis reviews of Jenin Freedom Theater in Palestine, Issak interviews Abdellah on opposition activity in Bahrain, Reem Nasr speaks with Abdul Hamid Siyam re current uprisings in Middle East. Hosts/Producer: Reem Nasr, Tamara Issak. Interviewees/Guests: Nadia Sakaf editor-in-chief Yemen Times, Hussein Abdellah of Bahrain-US Human Rights, NJ professor of politics and ME Studies Abdul Hamid Siyam. Topics: Yemen, civil rights, Palestine, Bahrain, US -Bahrain policy, Arab uprisings.)
  - April 19, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:50:38); (Saman reviews newly established ISPU aims on US and Muslim issues, Sarah Malaika speaks with Kurdiya about the founding and aims of his organic farm. Hosts/Producer: Saadia Aslam, Sarah Malaika. Interviewees/Guests: Shereen Saman of Institute for Social Policy and Understanding, organic farmer Norwich Meadow Farm Zayaid Kurdiya. Topics: US foreign policy, global Islam, Muslim Americans, world music, organic farming.)
  - April 26, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:51:04); (Lo speaks about experience of Palestinian activist Al-Jundi, members of Deaf Muslims talk w Nasr about their needs and work. Hosts/Producer: Tamara Issak, R Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: Palestinian co-authors Sami al-Jundi and Jenmar Lo, Ahmed Ibrahim and Nasira Abdullah of Deaf Muslims. Topics: Palestine, memoir, Muslim Americans, deafness, global music.)
  - June 14, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:19); (Discussion of the life and meaning of the Muslim prophet Ibrahim from an Islamic perspective, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: Muhammed Jaber of Bureau of Indigenous Affairs. Topics: Islam, Prophet Ibrahim.)
  - June 21, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:49:41); (Muhammed Jaber discusses his aspirations in basketball, Islamic spiritual life and his education at the University of Pennylvania In Philadelphia, Adawiya announces Betty Shabazz Awards and the service of community women, Rap recitation by Jaber. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: Muhammed Jaber of Bureau of Indigenous Affairs, NYC Women in Islam director Aisha Adawiya. Topics: Islam, Muslim American, Betty Shabazz awards.)
  - June 28, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:50:07); (Rap artist and musician Afendum, Reem Nasr speaks with Sayeed Arikhat Palestinian journalist on "Arab Spring", uprisings underway in Yemen, Syria and Libya, Malaika interviews University of Michigan professor Al-Sultany regarding the current Detroit Museum web-exhibition "Reclaiming Identity: Dismantling Arab Stereotypes". Hosts/Producer: Sarah Malaika, Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: Sayeed Arikhat Palestinian journalist, U. Michigan professor Evelyn Al-Sultany. Topics: Middle East political developments, uprisings, world music, rap music, stereotypes, Arab Americans.)
  - July 5, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:50:22); (Discussion of the life and meaning of the Muslim prophet Mousa, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: Muhammed Jaber of Bureau of Indigenous Affairs. Topics: Islam, Prophet Mousa, Moses.)
  - August 9, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:02); (Stern reviews famine in Somalia, discussion of the meaning of Ramadan. Hosts/Producer: Reem Nasr, Tamara Issak. Interviewees/Guests: Carol Stern US Fund for UNICEF. Topics: Ramadan, Somalia, famine, Muslim Americans, world music, listener calls.)
  - August 16, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:50:17); (Noor" Americaan Muslim band members speak with Tamara Issak about their spiritual music and innovation (introduction missing), Issak interviews Chicago-based food author Yvane Mafeh; Islamic spiritual music.. Hosts/Producer: Tamara Issak, Sarah Malaika. Interviewees/Guests: Music group California-based "Noor" members; Yvane Mafeh author of "My Hilal Kitchen". Topics: Ramadan, contemporary Muslim music, Muslim food, Hilal.)
  - August 23, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:44); (Segments from Tahrir archive Ramadan presentations--reading, music, poetry. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: segments from Tahrir archive. Topics: Ramadan, Spiritual poems and music.)
  - August 30, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:58); (Discussion of the life and meaning of the Muslim prophet Muhammed, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: Muhammed Jaber of Bureau of Indigenous Affairs. Topics: Muslim Prophet Mohammed, Islamic feast days.)
  - September 6, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:39); (Assad Siddique talks about goals and work of Muslim Lawyers Association, and with Lamis Deek address status of lawyers and law education inside Muslim American community, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: attorneys Assad Siddique and Lamis Deek. Topics: civil rights, law and Muslim Americans.)
  - September 20, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:27); (Young Egyptian activists in Cairo talk with Nasr about recent revolutionary activity and views, NYC-based playwright Ismael Khalidi regarding current play "Tennis in Nablus," Aziz reports from Lebanon recalling Sabra-Shatila massacre. Hosts/Producer: Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: young protest voices form Cairo Egypt, playwright Ismael Khalidi. Topics: Egypt, Arab American theater, Lebanon, Palestine.)
  - September 27, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:01:33); (Mohamed Ghani testifies about US bombing of Iraq and sanctions speaking in Baghdad with BN Aziz; BN Aziz reports to producer Hapte Selassi on Gaza response to 1993 Oslo Accord regarding Israel and Palestinians, phone calls. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: same as above. Topics: same as above.)
  - October 4, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:00); (Helena Suweri discusses art and Afghan-American community experience related to a current NYC multi-media performance. NY-based Afghan musician Zakaria Sherzad talks about living in US and his art. Khalil Meek from Texas talks about Muslim Legal Fund and its work fighting for Muslim civil rights. Hosts/Producer: Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: Helena Suweri of NYC multi-media event on the Afghan American experience, Afghan musician Zakaria Sherzad, Texas-based Khalil Meek of Muslim Legal Fund. Topics: Muslim Americans, Afghanistan, Afghan-Americans, world music, civil rights.)
  - November 8, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:31); (Political scientist Assef explains Eid Al-Adha and reviews his Palestinian childhood, career, and comments on Arab community aspirations and needs. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: NJ community activist Aref Assaf director of "Arab American Forum". Topics: Muslim feast Eid Al-Adha, Muslim and Arab Americans, listener calls.)
  - November 22, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:00); (Wahaj reviews social statistics of Muslim Americans discusses issues of Muslim American as targets of US surveillance, and organizing community members, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: NYC Islamic Imam Suraj Wahaj. Topics: Islam, Muslim Americans, US elections and Muslims, civil rights.)
  - November 29, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:08); (Disability conference panelists discuss educational value for families of disabled Arab Americans, world music, student Ibtihaj Mohammed reviews her training as a competitive fencer in school. Hosts/Producer: Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: NJ sportswoman Ibtihaj Mohammed, NJ disability service conferees Bill Gaventa, Rajeh Salloum, and Alia Soufi. Topics: Muslim Americans, Arab Americans, disability services, sports, world music.)
  - December 13, 2011, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:45:51); (Al-Azzabi talks about intervention regarding children's special needs, Zaid Saleh of Egyptian Assoc for Change discusses the role of Egyptian Americans in current Egyptian elections, US Circassians discuss Russian Olympics in Sochi and Sochi's history as Circassian locality. Hosts/Producer: Reem Nasr. Interviewees/Guests: educator Wafeh Al-Azzabi, Ziad Saleh of Egyptian American Assoc, Circassian activists Tamara Barsic and Daniel Merza. Topics: world music, education and disabilities, Egypt, elections in Egypt, Circassian rights.)